IAN WILSON BOLLING

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

(843) 323-2546 iwbolling@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ianbolling-79143813a github.com/iwbolling

CODING SKILLS

HTML
CSS and Sass
Bootstrap
JavaScript
Backbone.js
React.js
MVC architecture
Flux data flow

EDUCATION

The Iron Yard

Charleston, SC Front End Engineering (2017)

Trident Technical College

North Charleston, SC Criminal Justice, 37 credits (2008–2011)

OTHER SKILLS

Microsoft Office suite Adobe Creative Cloud suite 65 WPM typing speed Hardware installation Customer service

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I'm a junior developer with a passion for computers, coding and solving logic problems. I started with QBasic and video game modding in my youth, worked a bit with VisualBasic and have since started using JavaScript to develop web apps and games.

NOTABLE PROJECTS

TASKMASTER / COLLABORATIVE FULL STACK PROJECT MAR 2017 – PRESENT

- TaskMaster is a mobile-first, everyday app that allows users to quickly create to-do lists and share them with others.
- My responsibilities include project management through Trello, maintenance of Flux unidirectional data flow, the creation and rendering of multiple views and general styling.
- Tech stack includes Sass, Backbone.js, React.js, .NET Core, and IdentityServer.

BBC RADIO PLAYLISTS / FRONT END SINGLE-PAGE MULTI-VIEW FEB 2017

- Fetches API-based playlist data for BBC Radios 1 and 2, serving the data as separate views changed by route with no need for refreshing.
- Primarily Backbone.js based with MVC architecture implementation, grid system for styling adapted from Bootstrap.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Law Office of Jocelyn G. Bolling

Administrative Assistant, Courier (Apr. 2007–Dec 2013, Aug. 2015–present)

Jimmy John's Gourmet Sandwiches

Delivery Driver (Jan. 2014–Jul. 2015)